danielbrunoanjos@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/danielanjos

(801) 882-0501 • Idaho Falls, ID 83402

Hand-on expertise in investment, client relationships, business intelligence, financial reporting and analysis, and collaboration with team members. Translate requirements into solution, high-level business and system specifications, and portfolio of implementation tasks Persuasive and concise communicator; expert in modifying complex information for multiple audiences, and coaching subordinates for greater productivity and understanding.

Areas of Expertise include:

- Financial Planning & Analysis
- SSAS Data Models & Power BI
- Strong DAX Development Experience
- Python Programming
- Documentation & Reporting
- High Proficiency in SQL
- Training & Development
- Strong Team Collaboration
- Business Intelligence

Professional Experience

Lime • Orlando • Jan 2023 to Present

SENIOR DATA ANALYST - DATA SCIENCE RIDER

Maintain stewardship over financial data flows and prepare audit files. Monitor rejected financial records and optimize data pipelines.

Amazon • Idaho Falls • May 2021 to Jan 2023

FINANCE MANAGER - TECH FINANCE

Worked with data scientists and product managers to quantify the financial opportunity of ML models used for procurement negotiations and product assortment decisions. Audited ML model results and use financial metrics to recommend model improvements. Provided support for all Amazon Private Brands ML initiatives. Acted as a BI technical consultant for the Data Science team, build rapports with business clients to gather, document, and develop data and information requirements to answer the business questions.

Key Accomplishments:

- Identified a 2.3-Billion-dollar opportunity generated by a machine learning model used for automated vendor negotiations.
- Designed queries with complex data transformations and created new data pipelines used in ML models
- Developed a mechanism to calculate and track \$54,000,000 of free cash flow savings generated by ML models
- Used Python programing to combine multiple data sources, perform audit and automate the reporting process.
- Created a traffic plan for Amazon's Private Brands and a process to track 8-Billion customer page visualizations

MELALEUCA • Idaho Falls • Jun 2016 to Apr 2021

SENIOR FINANCIAL ANALYST

Improved organizational efficiency and performance by developing and consolidating financial reporting as well as managing project process through conducting analysis on products and promotions in global markets. Critically analyzed and evaluated Australia and Japan's financial statements to identify key variances, risks, and trends, while presenting market performance directly to management team. Regarded as the specialist in data retrieval and manipulation by utilizing SQL, SSAS Tabular models and Power BI. Utilized research acumen for identifying correct enterprise data stores to use and leverage deep expertise and statistical analysis. Steered efforts towards developing and implementing strategic solutions supporting a variety of survey enterprise level initiatives and large-scale insight projects across different business units.

Key Accomplishments:

- Drove phenomenal growth in company progression by increasing \$5,200,000 profitability yearly through the restructuration and revamping the Melaleuca's rewards program.
- Increased profitability by \$4,400,000 by optimizing Melaleuca's promotion strategy.

...Continued...

Significantly slashed \$70K in annual license expenses by eliminating unused licenses.

Internship Experience

AGRINORTHWEST • Kennewick, WA • Jul 2015 to Dec 2015

MARKETING AND DATA ANALYST INTERN

- Utilized research acumen for the categorization and capitalization organic market and proposed recommendations to increase organic acreage in a 70K acre farm operation.
- Streamlined and organized 10 years of data as well as designed advanced excel spreadsheets with interactive charts through the utilization of VBA programming.
- Led the development program aimed at training and mentoring team members regarding key business report.

DESERET CATTLE AND TIMBER • Panama City, FL • Oct 2014 to Nov 2014

BUSINESS ANALYST INTERN

- Delivered presentation of leadership development at a seminar in Rosario, Argentina.
- Fostered congenial relationships and professional communication with manager in diligently identifying places to build
 and establish a new office and housing facilities in a 380K acre property.

ELBERTA VALLEY AG • Elberta, UT • Jul 2014 to Oct 2014

PRODUCTION INTERN

- Played a vital role in administering 700 tons of daily corn silage storage as well as methodically produced yield report.
- Acknowledged as an integral participant in core projects with the collaboration of team members.

SOUTH VALLEY FARMS • Wasco, CA • Jul 2013 to Nov 2013

FINANCE INTERN

- Increased executive decision-making process by developing and reconciling financial reports for South Valley properties.
- Rendered exceptional support in updating and maintaining credit limits recommendations on international customers.

Education & Certifications

Master of Information Technology, Specialization: Business Intelligence and Machine Learning, GPA: 3.8 VIRGINIA TECH | Blacksburg, VA | Apr 2021

Bachelor of Science in Financial Economics, GPA: 3.8

BRIGHAM YOUNG UNIVERSITY - IDAHO | Rexburg, ID | Dec 2016

Certifications: Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) 98-364 Database Fundamentals

Languages: English and Portuguese, Conversational Level in Spanish